<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>new/s/leak</title>
    <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/</link>
    <description>Recent content on new/s/leak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 17:16:02 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 11:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/about/</guid>
      <description>new/s/leak (NetWork of Searchable Leaks) is a research project producing a piece of software that allows to quickly and intuitively explore large amounts of textual data. The tool will support journalists working with datasets like the Iraq War Diaries or the U.S. Embassy cables (both distributed by Wikileaks) or the hacking of Hacking Team. The goal is to provide a quick access to important entities (people, organizations, places) and their relationships, and how those things change over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentation</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 17:16:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/documentation/</guid>
      <description>new/s/leak is a browser-based web application with a backend of several docker containers orchestrated by docker-compose.
Getting started  Installation instructions User manual  Documentation  Development setup Preprocessing component (Javadoc) UI component (Scaladoc)  Publications Ballweg K., Zouhar F., Wilhelmi-Dworski P., von Landesberger T., Fahrer U., Panchenko A., Yimam S.M. Biemann C., Regneri M., Ulrich H. (2016) new/s/leak – A Tool for Visual Exploration of Large Text Document Collections in the Journalistic Domain, Baltimore, MD, USA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 13:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/demo/</guid>
      <description>Live demo We prepared three publicly available demo instances of new/s/leak. All demos can be accessed with the credentials username user, and password password
 250k English emails from the Enron Dataset 12k pages from German parliamentary investigation reports on the NSU murder case 27k articles from a multi-lingual collection of Wikipedia documents related to World War II (see also case study below)  Case study WWII   Ca.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 11:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/team/</guid>
      <description>new/s/leak&amp;rsquo;s interdisciplinarity shows in the diversity of the team behind it. There are scientists from Universität Hamburg and TU Darmstadt of different fields, and people from different departments of our media partner.
Department of Interactive Graphics Systems (GRIS), TU Darmstadt Tatiana von Landesberger, head of the Visual Search and Analysis Group, is one of our principal investigators, supervising the Information Visualization part.
Kathrin Ballweg, PhD Student in Tatiana&amp;rsquo;s group, carries out research around the graphical parts of new/s/leak, and is also responsible for conceptualizing the user experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imprint / Impressum</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/impressum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 11:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/impressum/</guid>
      <description>Angaben gemäß § 5 TMG: Technische Universität Darmstadt Fachbereich Informatik Fachgebiet Sprachtechnologie / Language Technology Prof. Dr. Chris Biemann Hochschulstr. 10 64289 Darmstadt Deutschland
Kontakt: Telefon:  +49 (6151) 16 - 25411   Telefax:  +49 (6151) 16 - 25412   E-Mail:  biem[ät]cs.tu-darmstadt.de     Verantwortlich für den Inhalt nach § 55 Abs. 2 RStV: Michaela Regneri Ericusspitze 1 20457 Hamburg
Haftung für Inhalte Die Inhalte unserer Seiten wurden mit größter Sorgfalt erstellt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New/s/leak at WissensWerte 2018</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2018-11-18-newsleak-at-wissenswerte-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 08:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2018-11-18-newsleak-at-wissenswerte-2018/</guid>
      <description>We present new/s/leak at a panel discussion at WissensWerte 2018, Germany&amp;rsquo;s most important dialogue forum for science journalists. On November 20, 2018 together with panelists from journalism, IT startups, and other universities, we will discuss how artificial intelligence contributes to journalistic work. In case of new/s/leak, we employ machine learning to automatically extract relevant information such as named entities and keywords from texts. This enables us to create interactive comprehensive visualizations of large text collections which contribute to a fast exploration for investigative purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted at EMNLP 2018 (Brussels, Belgium)</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2018-10-31-paper-accepted-at-emnlp-2018-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 13:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2018-10-31-paper-accepted-at-emnlp-2018-conference/</guid>
      <description>The paper &amp;ldquo;A Multilingual Information Extraction Pipeline for Investigative Journalism&amp;rdquo; focusing on the information extraction component of new/s/leak 2.0 has been accepted at the software demonstrations track of the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing The conference paper is available in the ACL anthology (here).
Abstract: We introduce an advanced information extraction pipeline to automatically process very large collections of unstructured textual data for the purpose of investigative journalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted at SocInfo 2018 conference in St. Petersburg</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2018-08-13-paper-accepted-at-socinfo-2018-conference-in-st-petersburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 13:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2018-08-13-paper-accepted-at-socinfo-2018-conference-in-st-petersburg/</guid>
      <description>Newsleak will be presented at the Social Informatics conference 2018 which takes place from 25-28th of September in St. Petersburg, Russia. The conference paper is published in LNCS series of Springer (here). A preprint can be found here.
Abstract: Investigative journalism in recent years is confronted with two major challenges: 1) vast amounts of unstructured data originating from large text collections such as leaks or answers to Freedom of Information requests, and 2) multi-lingual data due to intensified global cooperation and communication in politics, business and civil society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newsleak 2.0 pre-release software demo</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2018-06-04-newsleak-2-0-pre-release-software-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 09:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2018-06-04-newsleak-2-0-pre-release-software-demo/</guid>
      <description>Since the first version of Newsleak, a lot has been improved behind the scenes as well as in the front-end of the software. We want to encourage journalists, to try out a pre-release of Newsleak 2.0 on their own. For this, we provide a software demonstration. This demo is populated with ca. 26,500 documents collected from Wikipedia in four languages (English, German, Hungarian and Spanish) and mostly centered on the topic of World War II.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation at #EIJC18 &amp; Dataharvest conference</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2018-05-26-presentation-at-eijc18-dataharvest-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 09:52:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2018-05-26-presentation-at-eijc18-dataharvest-conference/</guid>
      <description>This Saturday, we present new/s/leak at the European investigative journalism conference (EIJC). Here you can find the slides of our presentation about &amp;ldquo;Information Extraction and Visualisation for Investigative Journalism&amp;rdquo;.
If you are interested to try new/s/leak with your own data, visit the Github page containing the Docker setup of our application.
In June, we will publish a detailed blog post on how to setup Hoover and Newsleak to analyze collections on your own machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dataharvest Conference #EIJC18</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2018-03-05-dataharvest-conference-eijc18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 13:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2018-03-05-dataharvest-conference-eijc18/</guid>
      <description>From Thursday 24 to Sunday 27 May 2018, the EIJC 2018 conference (European Investigative Journalism Conference) will take place in Michelen (Belgium). We as newsleak project will participate and discuss requirements and needs of our targeted user group. All about the conference you can find out on this website: https://dataharvesteu.wordpress.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funding extension</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2017-11-07-funding-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 13:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2017-11-07-funding-extension/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to announce that the new/s/leak project receives some additional funding from the Volkswagen Stiftung. Until summer 2018, new/s/leak will be extended and refactored to achieve the following goals:
 * easy deployment for own usage * comprehensive and detailed documentation * improved user interface * improved information extraction (better keyterm extraction, named entity recognition, support of user dictionaries) * support for multiple languages (among others english, german, spanish, french, arabic, chinese)  Follow the updates on this blog to see how far we got :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new/s/leak demo @ SPIEGEL</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-11-08-newsleak-demo-spiegel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 12:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-11-08-newsleak-demo-spiegel/</guid>
      <description>Now that we&amp;rsquo;re in the middle of new/s/leak&amp;rsquo;s home stretch, we had a final demo at SPIEGEL in Hamburg. After some exciting and productive development sprints, we proudly introduced the software to journalists, documentarists and software developers, who gave us the best feedback by playing around with the tool and becoming absorbed in using it. Some evidence:
  We also collected some more systematic feedback, which helped us prioritizing the remaining tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new/s/leak @ VIP</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-10-31-newsleak-vip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 09:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-10-31-newsleak-vip/</guid>
      <description>Last week, new/s/leak had its academic debut in the visualization science community at the Visualization in Practice Workshop, co-located with the IEEE VIS 2016 conference.
Here is the paper documenting the software with a focus on visualization. Needless to say that it&amp;rsquo;s always fun to present new/s/leak and get more feedback:
Thanks to everyone who came and visited us!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted @ VIS 2016</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-09-20-paper-accepted-vis-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 12:20:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-09-20-paper-accepted-vis-2016/</guid>
      <description>Our Paper &amp;ldquo;new\s\leak &amp;ndash; A Tool for Visual Exploration of Large Text Document Collections in the Journalistic Domain&amp;rdquo; has been accepted for presentation at the poster session of the Visualization in Practice Workshop, which is part of the IEEE VIS 2016 conference. The workshop will take place in Baltimore Maryland, USA on October 24-25.
VIS is one of the most important conferences in visualization science. new/s/leak fits perfectly in this year&amp;rsquo;s VIP workshop, the focus of which is design, development, distribution, and application of open source visualization and visual analytics software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new/s/leak @ ACL 2016</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-08-16-newsleak-acl-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 06:59:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-08-16-newsleak-acl-2016/</guid>
      <description>Last week, we presented new/s/leak for the first time in public: we had our demo session at the annual meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, which was held in Berlin this year. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t had the chance to attend (or you had and want to have some references now):
 Here&amp;rsquo;s the paper documenting our software (you&amp;rsquo;ll find a large part of the information from the paper in this blog, too) Here&amp;rsquo;s our poster (in PDF format)  Thanks to everyone who stopped by, especially for the great suggestions for improvements!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science behind new/s/leak II: Interactive Visualization</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-07-08-interactive-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 12:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-07-08-interactive-visualization/</guid>
      <description>We already explained the language-related data wrangling happening under new/s/leak&amp;rsquo;s hood. For the success of new/s/leak, our second scientific field is the game changer: interactive visualization. No matter how much accurate information we can produce - if we cannot present them to the user in an appealing way, the tool will fail its goals. So how exactly is visualization science influencing new/s/leak?
Your daily dose of visualization science It might seem easy to create some kind of visualization (with Excel or even pen and paper) - however, there are lots of pitfalls that you need to avoid to create good visualizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted @ SKILL 2016</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-06-09-paper-accepted-skill-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 06:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-06-09-paper-accepted-skill-2016/</guid>
      <description>Franziska, who designed and documented our requirements analysis for her research seminar paper (Studienarbeit), turned this into an article accepted for SKILL 2016, titled &amp;ldquo;new/s/leak - Anforderungsanalyse einer interaktiven Visualisierung für Data-Driven Journalism&amp;rdquo; (in German - English translation: &amp;ldquo;new/s/leak - Requirements analysis of an interactive visualization for data driven journalism&amp;rdquo;).
Congrats Franziska, and of course thanks for the excellent analysis!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted @ ACL 2016</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-05-23-paper-accepted-acl-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 06:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-05-23-paper-accepted-acl-2016/</guid>
      <description>Our paper &amp;ldquo;new/s/leak – Information Extraction and Visualization for an Investigative Data Journalists&amp;rdquo; was accepted for the Systems Demonstration Track at ACL 2016!
ACL is the most important conference for computational linguistics, and we will present new/s/leak there. Stay tuned for the final paper version - and our publicly available prototype.
Looking forward to meeting you in Berlin!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new/s/leak&#39;s impact on science</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-04-26-newsleaks-impact-on-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 13:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-04-26-newsleaks-impact-on-science/</guid>
      <description>There are many reasons why data journalism needs new scientific approaches, and we have discussed some of them at length. So far we haven&amp;rsquo;t talked much about the reverse claim, which is, however, equally true: this journalistic project also advances science. So why are our scientists so passionate about the new/s/leak project? And what kind of scientific challenges do we face?
/S/cience on a Mission All our scientists agree that it&amp;rsquo;s an invaluable experience to work on real use cases, solving real-world problems and collecting extensive feedback from real users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science behind new/s/leak I: Language Technology</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-04-08-the-science-behind-newsleak-i-language-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 13:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-04-08-the-science-behind-newsleak-i-language-technology/</guid>
      <description>Because of the Easter holiday season and several conference deadlines, this blog had to take a little break. Being back, we want to give a glimpse on the science behind of new/s/leak.
We have two camps of scientists working together: computational linguists contribute software that extract semantic knowledge from texts, and visualization experts who bring the results to smart interactive interfaces that are easy to use for journalists (after the computational linguists made the dataset even more complicated than before).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requirements Management</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-02-23-requirements-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 10:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-02-23-requirements-management/</guid>
      <description>User requirements management is something that happens far too rarely, especially in scientific software. (And it can definitely be challenging.)
For our project that brings together so different worlds of science and journalism, and also different academic disciplines, it&amp;rsquo;s even more important. We dedicated this a whole day on which we had Franziska and Kathrin over at SPIEGEL in Hamburg - and we proved that requirements analysis can be both, challenging and fun at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science &#43; Data Journalsim = new/s/leak</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-01-25-science-data-journalsim-newsleak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 15:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-01-25-science-data-journalsim-newsleak/</guid>
      <description>On January 1st, we officially started to build our &amp;ldquo;Network of Searchable Leaks&amp;rdquo; or, in short: new/s/leak. Our goal is to put the lastest reseearch of language technolgy and data visualization together to help journalists keeping their heads over water when meeting a dataset like the famous Cablegate. The idea is to have a network of all actors (people, organizations, places) and show who will do what, with whom, where, and when.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We made it!</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2015-11-25-we-made-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 14:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2015-11-25-we-made-it/</guid>
      <description>Happy news: VW foundation officially decided to fund our project with the working title DIVID-DJ: Data Extraction and Interactive Visualization of Unexplored Textual Datasets for Investigative Data-Driven Journalism. We are one out of eight projects funded as a part of the initiative &amp;ldquo;Science and Data Journalism&amp;rdquo;. Our goal is to create a piece of software that visualizes the content of large text data collections, to help journalists working with data leaks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/devsetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/devsetup/</guid>
      <description>Development setup  Follow the instructions for the user installation to get a working hoover and newsleak installation.
 Clone the newsleak Github repository
  git clone https://github.com/uhh-lt/newsleak.git  Preprocessing pipeline The preprocessing pipeline is a Java-based Maven project using Apache UIMA a base technology for information extraction.
Stop the newsleak containers and restart them with the dev container orchestration:
cd newsleak-docker docker-compose down docker-compose -f docker-compose.dev.yml up -d  This omits starting the newsleak-ui container and exposes ports of the remaining three containers: newsleak-postgres, newsleak-elasticsearch, and newsleak-ner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/install/</guid>
      <description>Installation new/s/leak is free, open-source, and deployed as a bundle of docker containers orchestrated by docker-compose.
The software requires a docker compatible operating system (Linux, Mac OSX, or Windows 10 64bit Pro, Enterprise or Education), at least 8 GB of RAM, and 3 GB of disk space. Also: the more CPU cores, the faster the indexing, information extraction, and visualization will run.
Prerequisites To install new/s/leak, you first need two other compontents:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>