<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General on new/s/leak</title>
    <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/categories/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General on new/s/leak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 12:56:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>new/s/leak demo @ SPIEGEL</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-11-08-newsleak-demo-spiegel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 12:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-11-08-newsleak-demo-spiegel/</guid>
      <description>Now that we&amp;rsquo;re in the middle of new/s/leak&amp;rsquo;s home stretch, we had a final demo at SPIEGEL in Hamburg. After some exciting and productive development sprints, we proudly introduced the software to journalists, documentarists and software developers, who gave us the best feedback by playing around with the tool and becoming absorbed in using it. Some evidence:
  We also collected some more systematic feedback, which helped us prioritizing the remaining tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science behind new/s/leak I: Language Technology</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-04-08-the-science-behind-newsleak-i-language-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 13:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-04-08-the-science-behind-newsleak-i-language-technology/</guid>
      <description>Because of the Easter holiday season and several conference deadlines, this blog had to take a little break. Being back, we want to give a glimpse on the science behind of new/s/leak.
We have two camps of scientists working together: computational linguists contribute software that extract semantic knowledge from texts, and visualization experts who bring the results to smart interactive interfaces that are easy to use for journalists (after the computational linguists made the dataset even more complicated than before).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requirements Management</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-02-23-requirements-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 10:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-02-23-requirements-management/</guid>
      <description>User requirements management is something that happens far too rarely, especially in scientific software. (And it can definitely be challenging.)
For our project that brings together so different worlds of science and journalism, and also different academic disciplines, it&amp;rsquo;s even more important. We dedicated this a whole day on which we had Franziska and Kathrin over at SPIEGEL in Hamburg - and we proved that requirements analysis can be both, challenging and fun at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science &#43; Data Journalsim = new/s/leak</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-01-25-science-data-journalsim-newsleak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 15:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2016-01-25-science-data-journalsim-newsleak/</guid>
      <description>On January 1st, we officially started to build our &amp;ldquo;Network of Searchable Leaks&amp;rdquo; or, in short: new/s/leak. Our goal is to put the lastest reseearch of language technolgy and data visualization together to help journalists keeping their heads over water when meeting a dataset like the famous Cablegate. The idea is to have a network of all actors (people, organizations, places) and show who will do what, with whom, where, and when.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We made it!</title>
      <link>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2015-11-25-we-made-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 14:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uhh-lt.github.io/newsleak/news/2015-11-25-we-made-it/</guid>
      <description>Happy news: VW foundation officially decided to fund our project with the working title DIVID-DJ: Data Extraction and Interactive Visualization of Unexplored Textual Datasets for Investigative Data-Driven Journalism. We are one out of eight projects funded as a part of the initiative &amp;ldquo;Science and Data Journalism&amp;rdquo;. Our goal is to create a piece of software that visualizes the content of large text data collections, to help journalists working with data leaks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>